<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<Elements>
    <Element symbol="H">
        <Description lang="en_us">
            [b][blue]Hydrogen[b/] is the simplest element you can think of. In its common
            form it's made out of a single [red]Proton[reset], with, most of the time,
            an [gold]Electron[reset]
            wandering around like a moon. However, it can be found
            in two rare variants: [b]Deuterium[b/] (with a single [green]Neutron[reset] and
            a single [red]Proton[reset]) and [b]Tritium[b/], which is made out of a Neutron
            and two Protons.
            [p/]
            Most of the Universe (say 75%) is made out of Hydrogen. On [s]Earth[s/] Mineworld,
            most of the Hydrogen is in its bi-atomic form H_2, which consists of two atoms
            of Hydrogen glued together trough what is known (with a fancy term) as
            [b]Covalent bound[b/].
            This just means that the two Hydrogen atoms share (most of the time happily)
            their own Electrons.
            [p/]
            Hydrogen is odorless, colorless (why can't we just say it's transparent?)
            and tasteless (yes, you've read this correctly).
            [p/]
            The [u]novel chemist[u/] might want to obtain [blue]Hydrogen[reset]
            as first thing. Hydrogen is easy to obtain: you just need a source of electricity
            (somebody said potato?) and some fresh water. The idea is the following:
            a molecule of Water (H_20 for short) is made out of two atoms of Hydrogen
            and one of [b]Oxygen[b/]. Those two atoms are glued together.
            We just need to pull them
            apart using electricity and observe the magic as it happens.
            [p/]
            [u]Precautions:[u/][br/]
            [li] [red]Explosive[reset]: Hydrogen is dangerous and together with Oxygen
            and a spark it causes a violent explosion.
            If you do not believe me, look up the Wikipedia page for Hindenburg disaster.
            [br/]
            [li] [magenta]Not tasty[reset]: yeah, do not use Hydrogen as salad dressing.
            [br/]
            [u]Uses:[u/][br/]
            [li] [red]Fuel[reset]: due to his high reactivity it is very useful as
            fuel. In particular for rockets. But also for cars. It is also very light,
            so you can use it to fill your Zeppelin (strongly discouraged, see above).
            The nice thing is that the discarded element from Hydrogen combustion is just
            Water.
            [br/]
            [u]Obtained from:[u/][br/]
            [li] [blue]Water[reset]: using water electrolysis
            [br/]
            [li] [gold]Methane[reset][br/]
            [li] [red]Stars[reset]: just need to reach for the sun and grab an handful.
        </Description>
    </Element>
    <Element symbol="He">
        <Description lang="en_us">
            [b][blue]Helium[b/] is the second element of the periodic table.
            [br/]
            [u]Uses:[u/][br/]
            [li] [red]Cryogenics[reset]: being liquid at even the smallest temperatures
            (Helium melts at [blue]1K[reset], but only with high pressure),
            Helium is quite useful to cool down stuff,
            without solidifying or condensing. This can be used to cool
            down superconductors (that can
            be used to power very strong magnets).
            [br/]
            [li] [red]Balloons[reset]: since helium is quite light, it can be used to
            lift balloons into the air.
            [u]Obtained from:[u/][br/]
            [li] [blue]Air[reset]: Helium can be extracted from earths atmosphere
            using its lightness and low boiling point.
            [li] [red]Stars[reset]: stars contain a big quantity of Helium.
        </Description>
    </Element>
    <Element symbol="Li">
        <Description lang="en_us">
            [b][blue]Lithium[b/] is the first solid of the periodic table of elements.
            It is very reactive and flammable, and tends to form bonds with almost anything.
            [p/]
            [u]Precautions:[u/][br/]
            [li] [red]Reactive[reset]: Lithium is extremely reactive, keep it away from
            water and possibly store it in oil.
            [br/]
            [li] [gold]Flammable[reset]: this element tends to catch fire very quickly.
            [br/]
            [li] [magenta]Friendly[reset]: this element tends to befriend many elements.
            While doing this, it tends to be rather explosive.
            [br/]
            [u]Uses:[u/][br/]
            [li] [red]Batteries[reset]: Lithium is used in Lithium Ion batteries.
            [li] [blue]Glass/Ceramic[reset]: Lithium Oxide can be used to facilitate
            the working of glasses and ceramics.
            [li] [gold]Lubricant[reset]
            [br/]
            [u]Obtained from:[u/][br/]
            [li] [blue]Electrolysis[reset]: of a solution of [red]Potassium Chloride [KCl][reset] and [blue]Lithium
            Chloride [LiCl][reset] (both salts).
            [br/]
            [li] [gold]Brine/Clay[reset][br/]
            [li] [red]Spodumene (Silicate)[reset][br/]
        </Description>
    </Element>
    <Element symbol="Be">
        <Description lang="en_us">
            [b][blue]Beryllium[b/] is a very light metalloid, the 4th element of the periodic table. It is
            quite toxic and contact should be avoided.
            [p/]
            [u]Precautions:[u/][br/]
            [li] [red]Toxic[reset]
            [br/]
            [u]Uses:[u/][br/]
            [li] [red]Alloys[reset]: Beryllium is very light and can be use to create metal alloys, together with
            Copper, Aluminium, Nickel, Iron.
            [br/]
            [li] [blue]X-Rays/Particle detectors[reset]
            [br/] [magenta]Mirrors[reset]
            [br/]
            [u]Obtained from:[u/][br/]
            [li] [blue]Beryl (Silicate)[reset]
            [br/]
            [li] [gold]Emerald[reset]
        </Description>
    </Element>
    <Element symbol="B">
        <Description lang="en_us">
            [b][blue]Boron[b/] is the 5th element of the periodic table. It belongs to the family
            of and is a blackish solid at room temperature.
            [p/]
            Interestingly enough, Boron does not melt, but instead becomes vapor when hot enough.
            This process has the name of [b]sublimation[b/].
            [u]Precautions:[u/][br/]
            [li] [red]None[reset]: Boron is quite Bor-ing.
            [br/]
            [br/]
            [u]Uses:[u/][br/]
            [li] [red]Fertilizer[reset]: some Boron compound can be used as Fertilizer.
            [br/]
            [li] [blue]Glass/Ceramics[reset]: Boron can be used to strengthen various
            glasses and ceramics.
            [br/]
            [u]Obtained from:[u/][br/]
            [li] [blue]Sodium and Calcium Borates[reset]
        </Description>
    </Element>
    <Element symbol="C">
        <Description lang="en_us">
            [b][black]Carbon[reset] is the 5th element of the periodic table.
            It is the
            most important building block of life forms as we know it.
            [u]Uses:[u/][br/]
            [li] [magenta]Plastic, Paint and Fibres[reset]: carbon can be made into many
            synthetic materials.[br/]
            [li] [blue]Carbon fibre[reset]: used as lightweight material for airplanes
            and many other things.[br/]
            [li] [gold]Graphite/Diamonds[reset]: for pencils and shiny
            blue rocks.[br/]
            [li] [red]Fuel[reset]: can be used as fuel
            in its many forms.[br/]
            [li] [green]Lubricant[reset][br/]
            [u]Obtained from:[u/][br/]
            [li] [red]Fossil fuels[reset]: carbon can be
            extracted from oil, coal and
            natural gas.[br/]
            [li] [gold]Graphite/Diamonds[reset][br/]
            [li] [blue]Carbon dioxide and monoxide[reset],
            infamous CO and CO_2, which
            is one of the many things killing life on earth.
        </Description>
    </Element>
    <Element symbol="N">
        <Description lang="en_us">
            [b][blue]Nitrogen[reset] is the most abundant gas in earth's athmosphere.
            In t's most common form, it is found in it's diatomic state N_2.
            [u]Uses:[u/][br/]
            [li] [magenta]Fertilizer[reset][br/]
            [li] [green]Coolant[reset][br/]
            [u]Obtained from:[u/][br/]
            [li] [red]Air[reset]
        </Description>
    </Element>
    <Element symbol="O">
        <Description lang="en_us">
            [b][black]Oxygen[reset] is the 8th element of the periodic table. It
            is very abundant in Earth's atmosphere. Generally is found in its
            diatomic form. It has a number of uses, due it being
            very reactive.
            [p/]
            Another form of Oxygen is [b]Ozone[b/], written O_3, which consists
            of three atoms of Oxygen glued together. Ozone also constitutes
            part of the famous layer surrounding earth, which has the, also very
            famous, holes. This layer, among other things, protects earth from
            nasty Sun's [purple]ultraviolet[reset] (UV) radiation.
            [u]Uses:[u/][br/]
            [li] [magenta]Yer know, breathing[reset].[br/]
            [li] [gold]Steel production[reset].[br/]
            [li] [blue]Welding/Metal cutting[reset].[br/]
            [li] [blue]Water treatment[reset].[br/]
            [li] [blue]Rocket fuel[reset].[br/]
            [u]Obtained from:[u/][br/]
            [li] [red]Air[reset][br/], which contains about 20% of
            Oxygen.
        </Description>
    </Element>
    <Element symbol="F">
        <Description lang="en_us">
            [b][black]Fluorine[reset] is the 9th element of the periodic table. It is a very reactive element and
            generally it forms a bond with itself producing F_2. In this form, it is a very toxic, very reactive
            yellow-ish compound.
            [p/]
            By itself it is not that useful, but it forms many useful compounds when bonding with other elements.
            [u]Uses:[u/][br/]
            [li] Teflon[br/]
            [li] Refrigerant compounds[br/]
            [li] Uranium refinement[br/]
            [li] Global warming (some say)[br/]
            [u]Obtained from:[u/][br/]
            [li] Fluorite[br/]
        </Description>
    </Element>

</Elements>